<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>buchh.org</title><link>https://buchh.org</link><description>buchh.org RSS feed</description><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Re: Why We Admire Zelensky</title><description>&lt;p>This is the letter I submitted to The New York Times&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/18/opinion/letters/high-school-letters-competition.html" target="_blank">student letter writing
competition&lt;/a>. Although my letter was &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/07/opinion/letters/high-school-student-letters.html" target="_blank">not selected&lt;/a>, I still like what I wrote
and am publishing it here&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. It is a response to an opinion piece titled:
&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/19/opinion/why-we-admire-zelensky.html" target="_blank">Why We Admire Zelensky&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>To the Editor:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I cannot stop from wondering, &amp;ldquo;Is this real life?&amp;rdquo; After watching the first
episode of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Servant_of_the_People_%28TV_series%29" target="_blank">Servant of the People&lt;/a>, both the name of Zelensky&amp;rsquo;s political party
and TV show he starred as president, my eyes were opened to the striking
similarities between the show and reality. His character and he were elected
for the same reason: &amp;ldquo;to bring professional, decent people to power.&amp;rdquo; As an
outsider, Zelensky&amp;rsquo;s story sounds like a fairytale, but it is not. This is real
life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I, along with the rest of the world, hold my breath as we watch Russia&amp;rsquo;s
invasion of Ukraine unfold, I have trouble accepting real life. My generation
does not know what to expect. We are the oldest alive to have never experienced
widespread global conflict. We did not live through the Cold War like my
parents; we never grew up during World War II like my grandparents; and we never
saw the end of World War I like my great grandparents. We fear what might happen
with more direct foreign involvement in this conflict. Despite the imminent
threat of death, Zelensky and the Ukrainians&amp;rsquo; resilience gives me hope that
democracy and freedom can prevail.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>One of the many benefits of having your own website :)&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description><link>/zelensky/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zelensky/</guid></item><item><title>How to Study for the SAT</title><description>&lt;p>When I first started studying for the SAT, I felt lost. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what books
I should be purchasing, which practice tests I should taking, or how much I
should be studying. I thought it would be helpful for me (a high school Junior)
to document my SAT studying techniques—even if it will only be helpful for my
sister, who will be taking the SAT in the next couple of years (as long as it is
still a relevant metric). By no means am I saying my method will work for you or
that it is the best way to study for the SAT, but it could be of use to some,
since it helped me gain 250+ points from my first practice test in August 2021
(85&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> percentile) to the December 2021 SAT (99&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup>
percentile). I don&amp;rsquo;t say this to gloat, but to add credibility to this approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my mind, there are three stages to studying for the SAT. If you want to score
above 1500, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get to stage 3, since your margin of error is slim.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of note, it&amp;rsquo;s notoriously difficult to improve the Evidence-Based Reading
section. You really just need to read actual books to do well, though the
methodology described below can help—just to a lesser extent than the other
three sections. I rekindled my love for reading&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> during &amp;ldquo;lockdown&amp;rdquo;
in 2020, so the Evidence-Based Reading started out as my strongest section;
however, it turned out to be my weakest section on my December 2021 SAT, since
my score in that section improved the least.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stage-1-understanding-the-content">Stage 1: Understanding the Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first thing I did was make sure I knew how to solve every problem. It&amp;rsquo;s hard
to practice when you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to get the right answer. Initially, I took a
practice test and then went through each problem individually, marking each
answer as correct or incorrect. On incorrectly marked questions, I checked to
see if I knew how to get the correct answer. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t, I would (re)learn the
material by watching videos I found on the internet&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. After this, I
grinded out 1,762 free practice problems on &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/sat" target="_blank">Khan Academy&lt;/a>. During this stage, I
would recommend doing a full practice test&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> on the weekends (at
least one every other week, though once a week is better). Completing practice
tests in full improves your concentration and allows you to become more familiar
with the testing format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know you&amp;rsquo;re past stage 1 when you feel stupid every time you get a problem
wrong because you know why the right answer is right.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sat-books">SAT Books&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I bought the book my tutor recommended (more on tutors below), but didn&amp;rsquo;t find
it to be too helpful. It is possible that I could have gained more from my SAT
book had I spent more time with it. My book—like most, if not all SAT books—was
so long that I was honestly overwhelmed by it. Outside of completing a few
assigned problems from my tutor, I only used my book to do extra practice tests
after I ran out of the tests provided for free by College Board. I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to
believe that purchasing an SAT book is not necessary, but by all means, buy the
one that someone you trust recommends. Maybe it will be exactly what you need.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sat-prep-courses">SAT Prep Courses&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While I didn&amp;rsquo;t take an SAT prep course, I think it could be a great option for
some people. If you have trouble with self-discipline and focus, an SAT prep
course would probably be helpful. If practicing on your own isn&amp;rsquo;t difficult, the
cost of an SAT prep course likely does not justify its high price tag.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stage-2-familiarity-with-the-test-format">Stage 2: Familiarity With the Test Format&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After doing many practice problems, I noticed patterns in the types of questions
covered on the SAT. Upon seeing a question, I immediately knew the type of
answer choices that would be available since I had done many similar practice
problems, just with different &amp;ldquo;variables.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Improvement in stage 2 mainly comes from doing lots of practice tests. You don&amp;rsquo;t
need to set aside 3 hours to complete a full practice test to improve in stage
2. Instead, do one section of a practice test each day. I&amp;rsquo;d still recommend
doing a full practice test on the weekend. Khan Academy is great for stage 1,
when you need to practice several of a certain type of problem to ensure you
really know how to do it. However, in stage 2, when you know the material, doing
a practice section is more helpful. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to be able to solve a problem
having done 5 very similar ones in a row; it&amp;rsquo;s a very different thing to get the
question right in the format of an actual SAT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know you&amp;rsquo;re past stage 2 when you start reading a question and already know
what College Board wants you to answer (make sure not to rush to the wrong
conclusion!).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sat-tutors">SAT Tutors&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I found meeting with a tutor to be beneficial during stage 2. I met with my
tutor three times (1 hour each time, totaling to 3 hours) and saw an increase of
~100 points on practice math sections. It was definitely time and money well
spent. If you can, try learning new material on your own, instead of with a
tutor, since your time with a tutor can be better spent elsewhere. My tutor
showed how to avoid common mistakes, taught me that I should never feel
ambivalent about any two answers, since there will only be one &lt;em>best&lt;/em> answer,
and gave me tips to better take advantage of the format of the SAT. I also
learned how to solve math problems in new, faster ways that weren&amp;rsquo;t taught to me
in school. These tips were not obvious to me on my own, but were extremely
beneficial in helping me improve my SAT score.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stage-3-pacing">Stage 3: Pacing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I got to stage 3 just a week or two before I took the December 2021 SAT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first started taking practice tests, I could barely finish a section on
time, but after enough practice, I had enough time to partially check my work a
second time. At this point, I needed to pace myself and slow down. I found I
scored better when I took my time when first answering questions, having just
enough time to thoroughly check my work once than when I rushed through the test
and had time to check my work twice. It was hard to convince myself to
meticulously examine my work after having already done it once. To score in the
1500s, it is critical to check your work, since you can&amp;rsquo;t miss many questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you get to the point where you need to slow down, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much else you
can do to improve besides calming nerves and gaining confidence by doing well on
additional practice tests.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timing">Timing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I highly recommend taking the SAT in August of the start of your junior year.
Because you have plenty of time before you need to submit an SAT score, you can
use the August SAT as a super low pressure environment to understand what it
feels like to take an SAT. Because this test date is several months earlier than
the PSAT, the &lt;em>only&lt;/em> opportunity to be selected as a National Merit Finalist, it
may not be optimal to peak in August. Instead, try to peak when your school
takes the PSAT and schedule an SAT close to that date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worst case scenario is really not that bad: you realize you need to study
more, but at least you&amp;rsquo;ll be more prepared for your next test and for the PSAT,
since you&amp;rsquo;re now more comfortable with the testing environment. The best case
scenario is quite good: you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the SAT anymore, since
you&amp;rsquo;re happy with your score. Either way, there&amp;rsquo;s a positive outcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also found it helpful to bring an analog watch with me to take the SAT.
College Board doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow for any watches that make noise (basically all
digital watches) or external timing devices&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, so an analog watch is
the only way to mange your time besides hoping there will be a visible clock.
Not only did I have peace of mind knowing that I would certainly be able to keep
track of time by bringing an analog watch, but I was able to use the watch as a
countdown timer by setting it to count down to 12:00 for each section. For
example, if a section was 25 minutes long, I would set the watch for 11:35 (make
sure to count by 5&amp;rsquo;s so you don&amp;rsquo;t make a silly mistake and think you have
more/less time than you actually have).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="closing">Closing&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Good luck on your SAT! If you made it this far, you care enough about your SAT
that I know you&amp;rsquo;ll study hard and do well.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Check out my &lt;a href="/reading">reading log&lt;/a>!&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>I will note that I had already completed both Algebra II and
Trigonometry before studying for the SAT. It will probably be harder to
understand all content that could be on the SAT if you have not taken those
classes.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3">
&lt;p>Take them on paper if you can. It is more similar to the
actual SAT. Khan Academy provides &lt;a href="https://www.khanacademy.org/test-prep/sat/full-length-sat-1/paper-sat-tests/a/full-length-sats-to-take-on-paper" target="_blank">free PDFs&lt;/a> to print. When taking the test,
you can&amp;rsquo;t search for a word or easily reference the text like you can online,
but you can write on equations when doing math problems.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:4">
&lt;p>See College Board&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://collegereadiness.collegeboard.org/sat/taking-the-test/test-day-checklist" target="_blank">SAT Test Day Checklist&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description><link>/sat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sat/</guid></item><item><title>Fantasy Football</title><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t watch football, I don&amp;rsquo;t follow football, and I don&amp;rsquo;t understand
America&amp;rsquo;s infatuation with football. You might not think these characteristics
describe someone who has played fantasy football for the past several years who
has found success, playing in two championship games last year, but it&amp;rsquo;s true of
me. A lack of passion for &lt;em>American&lt;/em> football has never stopped me from falling
in love with &lt;em>fantasy&lt;/em> football. I love drafting players, managing my (albeit
fake) teams, and pretending I played a part when one of my players has a big
game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is intended to be a beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to fantasy football, something a new
manager can read so they aren&amp;rsquo;t embarrassed/taken advantage by their coworkers,
family, or friends when added to their first fantasy football league. This guide
includes the basic principles that I have been using to successfully play
fantasy football.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I assume some general knowledge about American football and fantasy football,
such as positions and fantasy football scoring, but nothing that the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantasy_football_%28gridiron%29" target="_blank">fantasy
football Wikipedia
page&lt;/a> can&amp;rsquo;t provide.
At a basic level, you assume the role of the General Manager of a National
Football League (NFL) team, comprised of NFL players from different teams. You
draft a team, pick starting lineups, and earn points based on each player&amp;rsquo;s
performance, competing against other teams in your league.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="drafting">Drafting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The draft is one of the most important parts of fantasy football, but that
doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you need to spend hours researching or making a complex plan to
have a good draft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When making picks, it is paramount to evaluate a player&amp;rsquo;s value compared to
other players you could draft. The easiest way to do this is to compare a given
player&amp;rsquo;s Average Draft Position (ADP) to the current pick. If a player has an
ADP of 56, it means on average, they are selected with the 56th pick. If you
have the 2nd pick, you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t pick a player with an ADP of 56
without good reason, since there should be more valuable players available. The
player with an ADP of 56 should be available in later rounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should be able see each player&amp;rsquo;s ADP while drafting, but rankings can easily
be found online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ADP is just a good rule of thumb to estimate a player&amp;rsquo;s value. If you think it
should be different than ADP, use your own judgment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few common mistakes that beginner fantasy football managers make.
The first is picking a quarterback too early. If you pick for value using ADP,
you won&amp;rsquo;t run into this problem. Additionally, if your league has defenses
and/or kickers, many new players try to go for the best kicker or best defense.
These positions don&amp;rsquo;t really make a difference in the outcome of fantasy games,
so don&amp;rsquo;t pick either of them outside of the last two rounds. These positions are
easily replaceable and aren&amp;rsquo;t very reliable. Another common mistake made by new
managers is picking too many players from their favorite team. While it&amp;rsquo;s fine
to have a few players from your favorite team, if you have too many, when those
players have a bye week, you won&amp;rsquo;t have many players to put in your lineup.
Additionally, if that particular NFL team has a bad week, your fantasy team will
suffer as well. For the same reason you diversify financial assets, you should
diversify your players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watch mock drafts if you want to see how good drafters think about each pick.
These can be found online.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="in-season">In-season&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you want to win, you need to manage your team. The number one reason that any
fantasy football manager performs poorly is not paying attention to their team.
&amp;ldquo;Managing your team&amp;rdquo; means monitoring updates on your players so that you know
if they&amp;rsquo;ll be playing this week. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to win if you have inactive players
in your starting lineup.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="waiver-wires">Waiver wires&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>While it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get a great player in the later rounds of the draft, more
often than not, you&amp;rsquo;ll be wanting to find replacements for these players.
Luckily, there is something called the waiver wire that allows you to pick up
players that no one else has on their team. Rules on how the waiver wire works
varies from league to league, so ask your commissioner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To pick up someone from the waiver wire, you need to drop someone on your team.
You should do this if they sustain a season ending injury like an ACL tear. You
can also drop a player if they&amp;rsquo;re severely underperforming their expectations
and you can find someone better to add to your team. In both cases, check to see
what fantasy experts say about the player. Sometimes they sustain a minor to
mild injury that might have them out a few games, but are good enough to keep on
your bench. Other times, players just have a bad game. Just because someone
didn&amp;rsquo;t score very many points in your last matchup doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t
be on your team. Make sure that fantasy experts agree that a player should be
dropped before you do so yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many fantasy football experts post lists of good waiver wire pickups. You should
read about these players before your waiver wire closes. Every year, there are a
few elite players that show up out of nowhere and are available for free on the
waiver wire. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss out on the opportunity to get one of these
players for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="trades">Trades&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Only trade when necessary. Estimate if you will have a net gain in points if you
make a trade. Some experienced managers like to prey on new mangers and try to
take advantage of them by sending them unbalanced trades. Some leagues have
voting systems that prevent unfair trades from happening, but you need to be
able to determine if a trade is a good deal or not yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="picking-lineups">Picking lineups&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Believe it or not, there is some strategy in making the best lineup. If you are
slated to win, put in players that are consistent. You don&amp;rsquo;t need risky players
that &lt;em>might&lt;/em> score you a lot of points. You need these types of players (often
referred to as &amp;ldquo;boom or bust&amp;rdquo;) when you are supposed to lose by a lot. You can
find out if a player is &amp;ldquo;boom or bust&amp;rdquo; by researching them online.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="appendix">Appendix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You should now be prepared for a great fantasy season. If your season starts
poorly, don&amp;rsquo;t give up. Even the best fantasy football managers have bad years.
Unexpected things happen. The season is long and a lot changes in between the
start and end of the season.&lt;/p></description><link>/ffb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ffb/</guid></item><item><title>About</title><description>&lt;p>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Jonathan Buchholz, a junior at Thomas Jefferson High School for Science
and Technology chasing the Lord.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="essential-software">Essential Software&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>(n)vim&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alfred&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Little Snitch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>MailMate&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="colophon">Colophon&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This website uses &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank">Hugo&lt;/a> as a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_template_system#Static_site_generators" target="_blank">static site generator&lt;/a> and is hosted by &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank">GitHub
pages&lt;/a> for free. I have a more detailed description of my setup on my website&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href="https://github.com/JonathanBuchh/buchh.org#readme" target="_blank">&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;README.md&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My opinions change over time, so something on this site may not represent my
current views. Additionally, I am not a subject matter expert in any subject, so
take everything with a grain of salt.&lt;/p></description><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid></item><item><title>Projects</title><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://willston.org" target="_blank">willston.org&lt;/a>: A coding bootcamp at the Willston
Multicultural Center for students might otherwise not have access to computer
science opportunities. The bootcamp runs from June 13-17, 2022&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://buchh.fun/boatavg" target="_blank">boatavg&lt;/a>: Easily calculate your crew&amp;rsquo;s average 2k&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://rowtj.github.io" target="_blank">rowtj.github.io&lt;/a>: Offseason rowing opportunities,
training plans, summer competitions, and core and bodyweight workouts for TJ
Crew rowers, made by TJ Crew rowers. Instead of spamming our official chats,
we can instead send a link to this site that contains all relevant
information.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid></item><item><title>Reading Log</title><description>&lt;p>Books listed do not constitute endorsement and a high/low ranking does always
mean they do or do not align with my beliefs—rankings reflect the value I got
out of a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hall-of-fame">Hall of Fame&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Bible (Man Upstairs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to Win Friends and Influence People (Dale Carnegie)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Just Mercy (Bryan Stevenson)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not All of Us Are Saints (David Hilfiker)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Power of Habit (Charles Duhigg)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="2022">2022&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ranked">Ranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Why I Am Not Going to Buy a Computer (Wendell Berry)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Between Two Kingdoms (Suleika Jaouad)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slaughterhouse-Five (Kurt Vonnegut)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Excellent Sheep (William Deresiewicz)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crying in H Mart (Michelle Zauner)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This Is Water (David Foster Wallace)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Permanent Record (Edward Snowden)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Art of Invisibility (Kevin Mitnick)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="unranked">Unranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>City of Glass (Paul Auster)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ready Player One (Ernest Cline)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn (Mark Twain)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Fault in Our Stars (John Green)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="2021">2021&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ranked-1">Ranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>1984 (George Orwell)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can&amp;rsquo;t Hurt Me (David Goggins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deep Work (Cal Newport)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Atomic Habits (James Clear)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to Take Smart Notes (Sönke Ahrens)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Scarlett Letter (Nathaniel Hawthorne)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Sports Gene (David Epstein)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to Live (Derek Sivers)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Burglar&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the City (Geoff Manaugh)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Charlotte Temple (Susanna Rowson)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Tale of Two Cities (Charles Dickens)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Building a StoryBrand (Donald Miller)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ivy Study Tips (Mac Singer)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Things Fall Apart (Chinua Achebe)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Think Like a Monk (Jay Shetty)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="unranked-1">Unranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Allegiant (Veronica Roth)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Catching Fire (Suzanne Collins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crash Your 2k Erg Score (Brandy Mulligan)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divergent (Veronic Roth)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Harry Potter and the Cursed Child (J. K. Rowling)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Insurgent (Veronica Roth)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mockingjay (Suzanne Collins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Ballad of Songbirds and Snakes (Suzanne Collins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Hunger Games (Suzanne Collins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We Can Be Mended (Veronica Roth)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="2020">2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ranked-2">Ranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The Bible (Man Upstairs)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to Win Friends and Influence People (Dale Carnegie)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Innovators (Walter Isaacson)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Power of Habit (Charles Duhigg)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Subliminal (Leonard Mlodinow)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not All of Us Are Saints (David Hilfiker)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Is God anti-gay? (Sam Allberry)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caste (Isabel Wilkerson)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Becoming (Michelle Obama)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Born a Crime (Trevor Noah)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to Be an Antiracist (Ibram X. Kendi)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>White Fragility Robin DiAngelo)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Between the World and Me (Ta-Nehisi Coates)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dare to Lead (Brené Brown)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Third Door (Alex Banayan)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Linchpin (Seth Godin)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="2019">2019&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ranked-3">Ranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The Prodigal God (Timothy Keller)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Factfulness (Hans Rosling)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The 4-Hour Workweek (Tim Ferriss)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Tools of Titans (Tim Ferriss)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="2018">2018&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ranked-4">Ranked&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Just Mercy (Bryan Stevenson)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Language of God (Francis Collins)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mountains Beyond Mountains (Tracy Kidder)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Shoe Dog (Phil Knight)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description><link>/reading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/</guid></item></channel></rss>